So, the next topic, we are going to see else as tongue using the process working.
So, we are going to use one of the external tool that has been already in a GitHub repo.
It is a, it was developed from offensive Panda. The name of the tool was like shadow dumpers.
So, you need to download this and you need to compile this program.
So, after compilation, you will be getting a shadowdumper.exe.
So, there is, yeah, there is a huge step to compile this program.
So, if you did some Google, it will be easy to compile.
And I am not teaching how to compile that program in a evo way, ok.
Let me explain the shadow dumper technique basically, ok.
So, I already said, else as one of sensitive process, the EDRs and anti-verse software,
we will be looking into the else as process.
So, when you try to access the else as, so, automatically the anti-verse program,
our EDRs, it will be catching you and it will be terminating you from accessing right.
So, there is a method to bypass that, ok.
So, if you, if you able to clone the else as, ok, using some kind of APA function RTL clone,
like this one, RTL create process reflection APA, ok.
So, if you can able to clone the else as, ok and if, so after cloning another else as,
you can, you can access the cloned else as, ok.
So, let us take an example, there is an else as was running and another else as has been cloned.
So, you were not accessing the initial else as the sensitive process, which was looking
by EDRs and AVs, so rather than you are accessing your, your dumping a cloned else as,
ok.
So, basically there is a two else as now and you are, you are dumping the cloned else
as and you will be getting a crunch else from the else as, ok.
So, this will be done easily.
So, shadow number is an advanced tool to dump, to work with an else as, ok.
So, very, very, very good tools for penetration testing environment.
Let me show you how to do that, let me go to my shadow dumper program, which I have already
compiled, here it is, you can see the tool here.
So, let me copy this path, let me open a CMD, give me some stick, ok, let me open
the command prompt and let me go to the path D5, ah.
So, when I execute the shadow dumper, it was asking a few of the options.
So, this is the process working technique, we are going to use a process working the option
number 5.
So, I already said, the process working is like a cloning process and after the cloning
you are dumping a clone the process, ok.
So, let me proceed with 5.
So, now, got a handle of mirrored else as, so already the else as get mirrored and we got
a handle, let you some time action to dump an else as, so dump file will be saved under
the C public directory, the user's public till the dump was happening, that wait for some
time.
So, now, you can see we have the dump has been created and it was saved inside the public
directory.
So, you can see the file creation time 2020 and you can see the size of the file is
like 55 megabytes of data, so you can verify the date here, it is up to 20 and it is 55
megabytes of data has been here and it was in a raw file format, right.
So, no, don't worry about the different file extension that has been saved but our, but
our target is like dumping else as without any kind of detections or any kind of, yeah,
any kind of detection from the antivirus or edir platform.
So, now we got successfully dumped and dumped an else as from you by using the process
forking technique and you can see finally the cloned else as process has been terminated
automatically by this tool, that's where I said the shadow dump version of very, very
helpful tool to dump else as without any kind of detections, okay.
So, I hope we, you have a clear understanding about the process forking, the process
forking is basically we are using the RTL create reflection, sorry, create process reflection
API and we are cloning another one of them process and after cloning that process and
we are dumping that clone the process, okay, that's the thing we are using, okay.
Yes, that's all about the video, let's hop off and we'll meet you in our next video guys,
thank you, bye.